So, hello everyone, in this video we are going to work with our chat store.js file, we
need to make and modify some functions, okay.
So, let's start with the get messages, okay.
So, get messages and async is async function and it is a callback.
So, let's do this one and we need to give one comma so that it doesn't cause any kind
of error issue.
So, now after this, we are going to type everything inside of the try and catch logs,
try and catch and if some error occurs then we are going to console log that error.
Now, what we are actually going to do is we are going to hit a API point and we are
going to get one response, right.
So, for this one, so await access instance, access instance dot get.
So, we are going to get one response from messages.
So, message slash users, okay, I find now we are going to set everything like set the
users for the response dot data, whatever data which is coming from the response, we are
going to pass it to the users and we are going to display using the toast dot success.
So, toast dot success, we are going to display that to users fetched successfully, okay.
And for the cache block, we have this error and so for this one, let's do something.
So, for that one thing, we need to make one messages array, okay.
So message is, let's make this one empty array and after this, in the cache block, we are
going to write whatever the error that may come.
So toast dot toast dot success, toast dot error actually, error failed to fetch whatever
the message.
So failed to fetch messages, okay.
Since it is showing some error, so in that case, just go down console dot log error, right.
So now this one is done, now after this, what we are going to do is, let's make one another
function which is send messages.
So after this send messages, we are going to get the message, we are going to also send
the message in our chat up, that's why we are going to make this one.
And now similar methods, we are going to follow what this one const selected user, whatever
the selected user is, we are going to get that.
So, okay, let's do some, let's add some try and cache block, so try and cache whatever
the error comes, so console dot allergy error and toast dot error.
So selected users, okay.
So let's take one response, okay, so once again, let's do one thing.
And the try block, we are going to get the response.
So res equals to a wait x your dot, x your instance dot post, we are going to hit this request
and which path we are going to hit, that would be less messages, a one thing I think, okay,
that one I have did something wrong, messages, less send message, send message and then
for one particular user selected user dot underscore ID, okay.
So we have done that and after this, whatever the message is going to come, we are going
to fill it inside of the array, okay, so messages array, so message is dot dot dot.
You know why these three dots I have used actually right, so whatever the data that is
already there and whatever the data that comes from the response, we are going to just
say why is showing this, okay, so whatever the data that comes and whatever the data which
is coming from the response, we are going to set that, okay, that's why we are doing this.
So after this, we have done something wrong, no, let me check once, yeah one message should
be here, okay, so toast dot success message sent successfully, okay, save it and after this
for that thing also, message failed to send, message failed to sent, whatever the error,
but why this try block is showing some parsing error, anything I have done wrong, okay,
for this one, it will do get, so this message is this should be correct I guess, but
why it's showing like that, let me check messages is correct only and triple dots messages
comma response data messages is not defined, messages is not defined, okay, so here actually
the data whatever the data which comes and for that we are selecting the users and const
response equal to await access instance dot get, it's correct only right, but why it's
okay, so post should be here, okay, as I've done with this error, but still it's showing
some error, why, okay, this control and as see, there's some type of if I guess that's
why it was not showing, I have just passed it here, the payload included here and the
rest of the thing remains the same.
So now after this what we are actually going to do in the chat store, there's a set method,
okay, so it's actually getting from the mongos, this should not happen actually it's from
the juice and only, so set and get, I think that should be fine and after this, let me think
what we are going to do, okay, so we need to get that, like we need to use the use effect
to write, so in order to get messages to be loaded at the time of rendering, so get messages,
okay, and we should also pass the dependency array for get messages that should be the same only,
so brackets, get messages, okay, inside of this, I think it should be fine,
parsing error, there's some parsing error, bytes, parsing error, import get messages, okay,
it's done correct only, bytes, get messages,
there you are, oh, silly mistake, it should not be here, guys, actually it should be in the messages,
dot j6, we need to render there, right, nice use, so use effect,
and now here get messages, so we need to get that, and here also let's pass this, so
get messages, import use effect from react, so whatever the messages, like for this get messages,
we are passing this in the use effect of react, so it's going to preload or render at the time
of application loading, right, so that's what we are actually doing here, and for the messages,
let's go to the message input, so we need to set the states here, so we'll do one thing, import,
import use state, so use state from react, and after this, let's use this use state hook in order to
set some values, so const, let's get the messages, so send message function, we are going to get
it from the chat store, and we are going to use it here in some button, okay, so chat store input,
chat store from chat store, and this send message is going to import it from the chat store, and
after this, let's use some text whatever the text and set text method, and use state, after this,
suppose there's some image which we want to send, so for that one image and set image,
set image, and for that also we use the user state, so for all these values we are going to pass
it on, so in the button as you can see I have left some space already, so on click, for on click
method we are going to pass it here file input, file input, ref, okay, dot current, whatever the
current file is, then click, I think this should be correct right, it is a callback function, file
input, ref, dot current, it's saying that it is actually not defined, why, one way to second
place, okay guys actually I forgot to import this user of code, okay, so we imported this user of
code, and also we didn't define it, file input, ref equal to user of null, okay, so that's why
it was happening, so now after this, I think this video is long enough, but let me do one thing more,
for send messages and set text and images also we are going to do that also, okay, right,
so for reference we can take this as, wait a second, reference we can take this as
file input, file input, ref, and on change equals to,
we are going to make these functions right away, so handle image and whatever, so after this,
what we can actually do is, we can take all the values for this, like value equal to text,
right, so we have made that above, so value equal to text, and on change equals to E,
set text, and E dot target dot value, so whenever it's going to change, the change will be reflected
in the input, whatever it is there, so after this we can change this for, so set text is changed,
right, so we can change for the button also, so I've given some space here, so in order to
add some files, like add some changes here, so for button on click we are going to make one
handle send message, handle send message, we are going to create that one function also,
okay, so the video limit is like, it's quite extending and it's of 15 minutes only,
so we are going to see in the next video, okay,